

Stephen Swanson

Web | Software Developer

Details

Helsinki, Finland +358 406757425 swanson.stephen.h@gmail.com

Links

Portolio https://www.swansondev.me/

GitHub https://github.com/YB-BigSwan

LinkedIn https://www.linkedin.com/in/ stephen-swanson-h/

Programming Languages

JavaScript • TypeScript • Java • C#
• Python • SQL • HTML • CSS

Technologies

React • Next • React Native • HTML
• CSS • Tailwind CSS • Material UI •
Leaflet • Figma • Express • Node •
.NET • Blazor • Spring(Maven) •
REST API • Jest • Cypress • JUnit •
Postman • MySQL • MariaDB •
MongoDB • DBeaver • TablePlus •
Git • GitHub Actions CI/CD • GitLab
CI/CD

Skills

Teamwork • Communication •
Problem-solving • Adaptability •
Creativity • Critical thinking • Agile
Development • UX/UI Design

Languages

English (Native)
Finnish (B2)

Hobbies

Gaming • Playing/making music • Cycling • Hiking • Cooking

Professional Summary

Third year Business Information Technology student majoring in software development with more than 2 years of project working experience. Experienced in developing websites and applications, as well as testing and debugging. Excels in optimizing user experience and creating responsive and accessible web applications. I am currently seeking a trainee or junior position as I change careers.

Education and Certifications

Haaga-Helia UAS, Helsinki, FI • BBA Business Information Technology (Expected graduation 12/2024)

Relocating to Finland prompted a deliberate career shift, driving me to pursue a BBA in Business Information Technology, specializing in software development.

- Comprehensive course work, project work, and extracurricular projects encompassing frontend development (React, Tailwind CSS, Material UI, Jest, Cypress), backend development (Java, Spring, Maven, JUnit, Python, Rest API, Postman), and databases and database management systems, (MySQL, MariaDB, MongoDB, DBeaver, TablePlus)
- As a main accomplishment, I played a key role in developing a full-stack administrative tool for the Sibelius Academy. Here I worked collaboratively in a team as both a UX/UI designer and full-stack developer. Notable technologies utilized include TypeScript, React, Material UI, Express, Node, MariaDB, Jest, Cypress, Postman, GIt, RestAPI, and Figma for design, all managed with the Agile development framework.
- Participated in hackathons such as BRiDG3 24hack, where our team achieved 1st place in our category.

Finnish Integration Program, Helsinki, Finland • B2 Finnish Language certification (Completed 2021)

 Acquired a B2 Finnish language certification, contributing to effective communication in a professional Finnish environment.

Utah State University, Logan, UT, USA • BS Psychology (Completed 2018)

Work Experience

Career Transition, Helsinki, FI • Software Developer (12/2019 – present)

Men's Warehouse, Salt Lake City, UT, USA • Sales Associate (01/2019 – 10/2019)

 Established and meticulously maintained customer accounts, ensuring personalized service, and fostering long-term relationships.

Rite of Passage RTC, Logan, UT, USA • Therapeutic Mentor (01/2018 – 10/2019)

 Orchestrated comprehensive training sessions for staff, ensuring a high level of competence and proficiency in CPR, First Aid, and Safe Crisis Management.

Volunteer Work

Satakuntalainen Osakunta, Helsinki, FI • Web Administrator (01/2024 – present)

- Played a key role in maintaining the legacy website and overseeing Telegram/
 Email bots to ensure effective online communication.
- Led the development of a new, modern, and responsive website for the organization, contributing to an enhanced online presence.

Professional Reference

Available upon request